http://pentyrchrugby.co.uk/pages/08672e59-beda-4feb-af86-549f97ad7767/pentyrch-rfc-privacy-statement

Pentyrch RFC Privacy Statement
Pentyrch RFC Privacy Statement
Our promise to you
Pentyrch RFC promises to respect and look after all personal data you share with us, or is shared with us by other organisations. We will always keep it safe. We aim to be clear when we collect your data about what we’ll use it for, and not do anything you wouldn’t reasonably expect. We will never sell your personal data to other organisations, and will only ever share it in appropriate, legal or exceptional circumstances.
We are moving to an ‘opt-in only’ communication policy. This means that we will only send marketing and other communications to you if you have explicitly stated that you want us to. We’ll also ask you what you’re interested in.
Our marketing communications include information about our events, club business, ticket & sponsorship opportunities, recruitment, membership renewal
Where we collect information about you from
We collect information in the following ways:
When you give it to us DIRECTLY
You will give us your information in order to become a member of the Club.  We are responsible for your data at all times.
When you give it to us INDIRECTLY
Your information may be shared with us by independent sources. These independent third parties will only do this if you’ve indicated you’re happy for them to do so. You should check their privacy policy when you provide your information to understand fully how they will process your data.
When you give permission to OTHER ORGANISATIONS to share it
You may have provided permission for a company or other organisation to share your data with third parties, including charities. This could be when you buy a product or service, register for an online competition or sign up with a comparison site.
Depending on your settings or the privacy policies for social media and messaging services like Facebook, WhatsApp or Twitter, you might give us permission to access information from those accounts or services
The information we get from other organisations may depend on your privacy settings or the responses you give, so you should regularly check them.
When it is PUBLICLY AVAILABLE
This may include information found in places such as Companies House and information that has been published in articles/newspapers.
We may combine information you provide to us with information available from external sources in order to gain a better understanding of our supporters to improve our communications, products and services.
When we collect it as you use our WEBSITES OR APPS
Like most websites, we use “cookies” to help us make our site, and the way you use it, better. Cookies mean that a website will remember you. They’re small text files that sites transfer to your computer (or phone or tablet). They make interacting with a website faster and easier – for example by automatically filling your name and address in text fields.
As well as this, cookies can tell us the type of device you’re using to access our website or apps and the settings on that device may provide us with information including what type of device it is, what operating system you’re using, what your device settings are, and why a crash has happened. This information helps us understand how people are using our website and how to make it better.
Your device manufacturer or operating system provider will have more details about what information your device makes available to us.
2. What personal data we collect
The type and quantity of information we collect depends on why you are providing it. If you, for example, apply to be a member of the club we will usually collect:
Your name
Your contact details
Your e-mail address
Other personal information relevant to the membership application.
Where it is appropriate (for example Gym Membership) we may also ask for:
Information relating to your health
Information relating to the services you want to use
We will only ever ask for information that is needed to provide the service.
If and when we collect and manage information from children, we aim to manage it in a way which is appropriate to the age of the child.
If a child is under 16 we will seek consent from a parent or guardian before collecting their information.
3. How we use the personal data we collect
What we use your information for, depends on why you are providing it. We will mainly use your data to:
Provide you with the services, products or information you’ve asked for:
For example:
Club membership
Gym membership
Volunteering
Where you are a registered player, information pertaining to training, matches, fundraising activites and activities relating to your playing activities at the Club.
Access to this data will always be limited to appropriate individuals with a legitimate interest in providing these services.
If you enter your details onto one of our online forms, and you don’t ‘send’ or ‘submit’ the form, we may contact you to see if we can help with any problems you may be experiencing with the form or our websites.
Method of communication
We will contact you via the e-mail address you provide.
If your child is a member of the mini & junior section, Team Managers will also contact you through the telephone number you provide for information regarding training & match notification this is usually done through Teamer & What’s App.
To send you Direct Marketing
We will only ever contact you with direct marketing about our Club activities and campaigns with your explicit consent. We will also include information on how to opt out when we send you marketing.
We do not sell or share personal details to third parties for the purposes of marketing. But occasionally, we may include information in our communications from partner organisations or organisations who support us.
If you change your mind at any time, and no longer want to hear from us, that’s fine. Just let us know when you provide your data.
To keep a record of your relationship with us
It’s important for us to have clear records on how you’ve interacted with us. This helps us to make sure your experiences of Pentyrch RFC are the best they can be.
We may also collect and retain your information if you send feedback about our services, give us a compliment or make a complaint.
To understand how we can improve our services, products or information
We believe it’s important to make sure that all of our services are the best they can be.  That’s why we ask for feedback and evaluate them.
We may get in touch to ask you about your experiences with the Club. There’s no obligation to take part, but it really helps highlight ways we can make things better in future.
4. Sharing your data
We do not sell or share personal details to third parties for the purposes of marketing. We will only share your details with third party organisations when it’s necessary to;
Provide you with the services you’ve asked for
We will make sure you’re happy for us to do this before anything happens and will explain who we are sharing the data with
Administer your participation in any of our services
Comply with Health & Safety regulations
If we ever need to share data for these purposes, we will always take the utmost care, make sure only essential data is transferred, and that it’s done so securely and safely.
Exceptional circumstances
Pentyrch RFC may also be required to share your details in exceptional circumstances. For example, where legally required by the police, regulatory bodies or legal advisors.
We will only ever share your data in other circumstances if we have your explicit and informed consent.
5. How we keep your data safe and who has access
We make sure that there are appropriate measures and controls in place to protect your personal details. For example our membership forms, once processed, are held securely in a locked room at the Club.  During processing these forms are kept in a secure place by a member of the Committee.
We may need to disclose your details if required to the police, regulatory bodies or legal advisors.
We will only ever share your data in other circumstances if we have your explicit and informed consent.
6. Keeping your information up-to-date
We try and keep our records up-to-date so we send you the most relevant information, using the correct contact details.
If your personal details change, we’d really appreciate it if you let us know.
Where possible we use publicly available sources to keep your records up to date; for example, the Post Office’s National Change of Address database and information provided to us by other organisations as described above.
Your ‘Right to Know’ what we know about you, make changes or ask us to stop using your data.
You have a right to ask us to stop processing your personal data, and if it’s not necessary for the purpose you provided it to us for we will do so.
You have a right to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you. If there are any discrepancies in the information we provide, please let us know and we will correct them.
If you want to access your information, send a description of the information you want to see and proof of your identity by post to Data Controller, Pentyrch RFC, Parc y Dwrlyn, Pentyrch. We do not accept these requests by email. This is so we can make sure that we only provide personal data to the right person.
Changes to the Policy
We review this policy annually and may update it from time to time. If we make any significant changes in the way we treat your personal information we will make this clear on our website or by contacting you directly.
Updated July 2018.
Please wait as the server processes your request. Do not attempt to refresh the page.
